Seidenberg, Jacob Additional Arbitration Files 5773
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files
1979-1985
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Seidenberg, Jacob
5773
8 cubic feet
8 linear ft.
Records.
5702264
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, February 16, 2016
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, February 16, 2016
Biographical / Historical
Dr. Jacob Seidenberg (1914-1996) was a government official who specialized in labor arbitration and non-discrimination contracts, and wrote extensively on labor law and negotiations. He graduated from Temple University in 1937 and received a law degree from the University of Pennsylvania Law School in 1941. During the 1940s he was an attorney with the U.S. War Department, the National War Labor Board and the National Wage Stabilization Board. In 1948 he went to graduate school at Cornell University, from which he earned his Ph.D. in industrial and labor relations in 1951. In 1951 he joined the staff of the President's Committee on Government Contract Compliance. The Committee was abolished by President Dwight D. Eisenhower in August 1953 by Executive Order 10479 and was succeeded by the President's Committee on Government Contracts. Seidenberg was appointed Executive Director of the new committee and served until January 1960 when he resigned to become a full-time labor arbitrator. The Committee was responsible for enforcing non-discrimination clauses in government contracts, worked with private businesses to help them overcome job discrimination, and developed educational programs against ethnic and racial discrimination. The chairman was Vice President Richard Nixon, and the vice chairman was Secretary of Labor James P. Mitchell. In later years Seidenberg served on a number of boards of inquiry involving labor disputes. From 1970 to 1975 he was chairman of the Federal Services Impasses Panel which settled deadlocks in federal labor negotiations.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: check card catalog
Arbitration, Industrial.; Seidenberg, Jacob.
5702264
- UP - RYA - Section XI New York Dock Conditions (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Harrah's - Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union - Local 25 - AAA - 144 30 0705 83 J (Box 1, Folder 2)
- GPO - CTU FWCS (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Washington Hospital Center SEIU - FMCS (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Social Security Ad AFGE Local 3615 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Dunn Carter - UMWA (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Continental Telephone of VA - CWA Local 2275 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Westinghouse Electric Corp. - Federstion of Westinghouse Independent Colonial Employees AA (Box 1, Folder 8)
- GSA - Capitol Region (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Wilmington Housing Authority Open - Local #14 AAU (Box 1, Folder 10)
- TWU Local 290 - SEPTA AAA (Box 1, Folder 11)
- WMATA - Local 2461 FMCS (Box 1, Folder 12)
- US Postal Service - APWU (Research and Development Laboratories) (Box 1, Folder 13)
- United Parcel - IAMAW Local 1486 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- WGL - IUGW Dorsey (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Washington Post ITU Local 101 Panel (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Public Law Board no.3574 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Anne Arundel County Boaard of Education (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Public Law Board no.3866, Disputes (Box 2, Folder 1)
- National Mediation Board (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Emergency Board no.209 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Railroads (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Public Law Board no.2037: Conrail - BRAC (folder 1 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Scope and Contents
  Vol. IV
- Public Law Board no.2037: Conrail - BRAC (folder 2 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 6)
- NMB Hearing; AAA (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Harrah's Marino Casino Hotel and Employees and Restaurant Employees Union Local 54 AAA (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Quaker City Motor Parts Warehouse Employees Local 130 AAA (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Burris food Distributing Teamster Local 355 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Singer Co./Link Division IAMAW Dist. 67 Local 1140 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Kaiser - Georgetown Community Health Program Health Professional Association (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Ship Shape Maintenance Co. Service Employees International Union, Local 82 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- SEIU Int. Union - OPEIU Local No. 2 AAA (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Social Security Administration (Health Care Administration AFGE Local 1923) (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Hercules Inc. OCAW local 3-495 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- W. R. Coroce Co. Int. chemical Workers (Box 3, Folder 10)
- WMIATA - ATU Local 689 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Superior Beverages - Brewery and Beverage Drivers Local Union No. 67 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Central Transit Mgt Co. ATU Local 1544 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- SUN Refining Marketing Co. OCAWU - Local 8 - 901 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Montgomery county Public Schools MCEA - AAA (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Harrod's Cosmo - Local 54 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Eastern Air Lines - Boston (Box 3, Folder 17)
- St. Mary's County Public Schools (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Frontier - ALPA (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Florida Power Corp. IBEWU (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Pleadings + Agreements (Box 3, Folder 21)
- WGL - IUGW Townsend Grievance (Box 4, Folder 1)
- FEC Highway Dispatch Co. (Box 4, Folder 2)
- empire Steel Castings (Box 4, Folder 3)
- American Packaging Corporation (Box 4, Folder 4)
- WJAA - TV - NABET (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Westvaco - Inc. Printing Graphic Communications - L -690 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Draper Corp - IAMAW Local 352 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Republic Airlines, Inc. Association of Flight Attendants (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Chesapeake Paper Board Co. and UPIU Local 652 AAA (Box 4, Folder 9)
- United Parcel Service and Local 355 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- UTU - Missouri-Kansas-Texas RR Co. (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Virginia Concrete Company (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Georgetown University and District 1199E (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Washington Hospital Center and SEIU Local 722 FMCS (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Tronsall and Teamsters Local 557 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Tri-State Corp. and ILGWU (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Georgetown University andd District 1199E AAA (Box 4, Folder 17)
- SEPTA and TWU Local 234 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- UP System and BLE (NY Dock) (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Safeway Stores and Local 400 UFCU (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Safeway and Teamsters Local 639 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Allied and USWA #12103 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Public Law Board no.3444 LIRR and RYA (Box 4, Folder 23)
- ACME Markets, Inc. and UFCW Local 1357 AAA (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Industrial Union Dept. (AFL-CIO) OPEIU (Box 4, Folder 25)
- William M Young Lumber Co. and General Teamster Local 326 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Office Movers Inc. and Local 557 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Eastern Air Lines and TWU Local 553 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Public Law Board no.3314 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Washington Post and IAMAW Lodge no.193 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Louisville Gas and Electric and IBEWU Local 2110 (Box 4, Folder 31)
- AME Markets and UFCW Local 72 (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Pacific Corp and Local 2268 (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Jacob Seidenberg, Esq. and UFCW Local 56 (Box 4, Folder 34)
- WJLA - TV and NABET Local 31 (Box 4, Folder 35)
- Proposal for a New Basic Agreement between The Patent Office Professional Association and The Patent and Trademark Office, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Oct 30
- Patent and TM Office Documents (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Seidenberg; Arbitration (folder 1 of 2) (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Seidenberg; Arbitration (folder 2 of 2) (Box 5, Folder 4)
- BLE Study Commission Established Arbitration of POPA - US Patent + Trademark Office (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Public Law Board no.1348 Case 65 AW Briston (Box 5, Folder 6)
- UTU (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Public Law Board no.3950 Case No. 1 and No. 2 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- UTU (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Special court Misc. 76-1 January 31, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Special Court Misc. no. 76-1 January 31 Vol. II, III, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Special Court Misc. no. 76-1 January 31 Vol. V - VI, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Special Court Misc. no. 76-1 January 31 vol. 1; testimonies of Alfred E. Myles, Maynard E. Parks, Dr. Lewis M. Schneider (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Regional Rail reorganization act of 1973 (folder 1 of 3) (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Regional Rail reorganization act of 1973 (folder 2 of 3) (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Regional Rail reorganization act of 1973 (folder 3 of 3) (Box 6, Folder 7)
- AAA Truck Drivers and Helpers Local Union No. 355 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Public Law Board no.3853 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Flight Engineers and operations Training Instructors Pan American World Airways, Inc. (Box 7, Folder 3)
- T H Inman (Box 7, Folder 4)
- JFK PCA (Box 7, Folder 5)
- AFSA Oct 7-8, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- FPA vs. OPEIU, Local 2 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Security Administration Office of assessment and American Federation of government Employees council of field Assessment Locals June 22, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Former N.P. Engineers (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Jacob Seidenberg (Box 7, Folder 10)
- General Agreement: RCA Corp + International Federation of Professional & Technical engineers AFL-CIO Local 241 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Agreement Between The National Railroad Passenger Corporation (AMTRAK) Northeast corridor and BMWE (Box 8, Folder 2)
- ALPA and Republic Airlines (Box 8, Folder 3)
- AFGE - Office of Hearings and Appeals (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Office of Hearings and Appeals, social Security Administration - Local 3615, American Federation of government Employees, AFL-CIO (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Seidenberg Hearings and Corr. (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Agreement between Social Security Administration and American Federation of Government Employees June 11, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Seidenberg appeals and Corr. (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Agreements (Box 8, Folder 9)
- SSA - AFGE Aug 31, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Schedule of Wages & Rules Illinois Central Gulf Railroad (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Collective Bargaining in Public Employment and the Merit System (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Employment discrimination Marshall, et al. (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Studys (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Social Security Administration National Council SSA (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Conference Board Reports Handbook of Union Government Structure and Procedures (Box 8, Folder 16)
- Social Security Administration and AFGE local 3515 (Box 8, Folder 17)